[Music]
hey how's it going good how are you Dion
good see yeah really good a while yeah
how been great to see you where are you
joining us from are you back are you
home in the Bay Area I am yeah I'm
looking at the Salesforce Tower right
now oh nice awesome awesome sounds good
well thanks so much for for taking the
time to chat uh with us a little bit
about kind of AI development I know that
uh vel's gone through and has built some
really cool AI developer tours and
you've gone through um some interesting
changes there so excited to uh to learn
a little bit about that um with you so
to to start with if we could go back in
time a little bit before we go um to
where we are now and into the future uh
I was curious about kind of when the
birth of this form of the AI uh
Revolution kind of kicked in um for you
like when did it first hit you and like
were you skeptical at first and was
there kind of an aha moment where you
like oh maybe there's actually something
to this uh llm
thing yeah like so I joined for S it's
not almost been three years uh two and
whatever three qus which was so that was
early
2022 and so kind of it hadn't happened
yet right um but I also it came from
Google where I think Sunder declared the
company AI first maybe 2018 and I had
spent a lot of time with this stuff
there was some internal things going
around where people got really confused
about you know how good this AIS were
getting and so I was kind of primed on
it but then I think I went through the
same Transformations everyone else where
you try chbt and you realize holy crap
this is like this is this is it this is
going to
happen nice and then uh when you're
you're at versel and then that's all
kicking in um I assume that the kind of
you know the company kind of gathered
together a little bit to see like what
what does this mean to us what was what
was that like what came out of that yeah
I think that I mean we've been going
through it through many dimensions um
the first thing we really got lucky like
so we uh we actually that was my first
project kind of getting into Market it
had been under way a little bit but we
changed our our function execution
infrastructure to be uh built on a net
CPU basis and that was done for like all
kinds of reasons but when one minute AI
API calls came out it was an incredible
competitive advantage to have this
product in in in our hands which was
really good at this um and that's where
we just got lucky because it was
literally done the moment people
suddenly wanted to do this and but yeah
obviously we had to like think about
like there's a disruption going on I
think the we are in the broader like
developer experience space where and I
think that's the the fair to say it's
the early adopter for like more advanced
AI
transformation and so we absolutely we
thinking about like what is what's our
place in this world and I'm I'm so happy
with our answer because I feel super
native to what we do we have um we're a
framework company we we make nextjs we
support SP and many other Frameworks
like on the on the JavaScript side and
so it was kind of obvious that you know
we should make a framework for building
AI applications so that's the AISD which
has been incredibly successful in the
kind of typescript community for
building AI applications and our angle
there was to say okay there's like there
is some stuff out there from from other
companies but it feels really like
framework and advanced but nobody knows
what application people want to build so
you can't build a framework yet it's too
early right so with the AISD it's kind
of it's lowlevel utilities that you're
going to need but it doesn't like
prescribe you about anything so that was
our angle number one and the angle
number two was uh vzer which is our kind
of tool for getting people started on
front of development getting projects
kicked off and having an expert system
for for the Frameworks that we that we
support and and so again like that's
kind of a you know relatively obvious
thing that that um I think makes sense
for us to do and thankfully it's it's
very very successful got it awesome yeah
can you explain a little bit more what
v0 actually is and and kind of how it
really came about and and grew and got
good and totally I I mean it it actually
has gone through a bunch of iterations
but the initial one was that I think
like everyone who was think thinking
about the space is you had jbt jbt was
in llm let's squ a text and
HTML is just text everyone was kind of
obviously you need these guys to like go
and make uh web pages and but the thing
was if you tried like a year and a half
ago it would not do a good job like it
it would make something crappy that that
uh would look ugly and and and and
didn't
work and one of that was like one of the
crazi inside so we had a few folks in
San Francisco pretty remote company but
everyone was kind of in the same room
we're hacking a little bit and someone
like literally raised their harm and so
was like Hey Hey I I got it to work it's
good like I have the AI it makes web
pages and and it looks amazing um and
the so that was a good moment but then I
realized
that apparently that was the easy part
like getting a user experience together
that would actually make sense to
developers uh took us like actually
quite a while quite a bit of iteration
because I mean we start with kind of
just hacking a chatbot to be kind of in
this form and then we we actually came
out shipping something that looked quite
different that was very visual
focused and but I will also admit that a
year later roughly we kind of move back
to more of a chat interface so we're
kind of still figuring out what the
right user experiences but that was kind
of our our journey um just literally
yesterday we shipped a pretty major
release that uh changes vzer to be able
to build full
applications and have like real-time
preview while you iterate it on the on
the kind of chat interface and then the
ability to to deploy to production as
well it has access to like your verell
environment variable so it can just vary
your database all these things like it's
pretty pretty exciting stuff that's
awesome that initial kind of aha it's
actually kind of working moment was that
based on new models new prompting new
like what what enabled that initial like
I think this is actually gonna maybe
work so I think the inside that that we
had um we discovered literally because
it was in the AI right um the the the
inside was and it's such a crazy
coincidence that it worked is that AIS
are good at
Tailwind which is this new CSS framework
or way of writing CSS where you actually
write all the CSS and classes
where like this every CSS 11 has like a
class Associated and you just write it
out so it's basically like a uh it's
basically inline CSS in a in a slightly
more sustainable way than in L
CSS and like so this was at a time where
open AI was kind of leading the pack but
they had a model you know for the
longest time you probably remember the
precise cut off day was kind of like was
December 2021 or something like that
right and and and so the funny like the
The Coincidence is that Tailwind at that
moment is exists
and it's kind of popular but it's not
like today today it's like super popular
but it's it's already popular so there's
there's enough training data like in the
model that it actually is good at this
and and the kind of the Insight is that
the models of that time at least they
were really bad at saying okay I'm going
to write some CSS and I'm gonna like
write their right HTML or the other way
around like it wouldn't work but it
could re do it really well in one go
because it's all now one bundle and so
that was kind of the the step function
that while HTML in generation was bad
Tailwind generation inside of HTML was
really good and so that was kind of the
unlock that went from this is kind of
crap to oh no this is actually G to be a
thing that's so interesting because I've
often wondered about kind of the what is
The Sweet Spot of data for some of these
things around like uh if you have
something that's really popular but it's
popular with the masses so much that
kind of that
average of it is like kind of meh uh
versus like something that's a little
bit not quite as popular but the code
that has been written with it has been
written by like the early adopters maybe
more expert coders so maybe it can be
really good versus something brand new
where there's just nothing in the
training data like are we gonna have
King makers happening like I wonder how
it's going to evolve from here there's
certainly like a i there is a possible
future where there will be less
Innovation because the AI just has kind
of picked its thing and it's not going
to learn anything new if people stop
writing you know legit code by
themselves that's like a thing that
could actually happen yeah oh man that's
fascinating um you spoke about the ux
choices I remember when I first used
vzer and uh from a prompt I just got
multiple versions to start from instead
of uh uh instead of just having one
right and like um I thought that was
interesting from a standpoint of both
llms are really good at giving you
multiple options and there's variants
baked in and everything else and also
the PTSD that uh that I have that maybe
you have a little bit of going from the
10 Blue Links of Google where it can
hide so many sins where if a really good
result is the second one that's a great
result for the human whereas if you have
a you know Google assistant or Alexa
where it like comes back with its one
and it's not perfect you lose trust um
was that something that was kind of also
thought of like early on and there are
the there other ux choices that you've
made that like kind of work well within
this probabilistic world that we have
with llms yeah I feel like lots of this
actually just related to also the how
the quality of the llms and and how good
people are prompting and the
introduction of multimodal they all kind
of changed um something about this
so when VOR came out multimodal model
weren't really a
thing and so there was you couldn't
upload a design you couldn't say hey
make me this but kind of get the vibe of
this which is like a very good prompting
technique for vzer these days but that
wasn't around and and people would just
say you know I want a dashboard for
x and and then you know if you would do
that it you want to add a little bit of
creativity but you don't know what they
want right so like that that really
helps to make full version and and
hoping that one of them is going to be
good yeah so yeah that notion yeah the
notion of like elaboration I think is
fascinating right and it's
like and even subtle things like I was
kind of surprised in a tool that I built
before where um I assume that developers
have been using chat GPT type things and
we'll start just kind of chatting away
and a lot of them would just do new chat
sessions zero shots from scratch and so
by adding to the bottom of every chat
like a question kind of asking for more
um taught them how to do it and allowed
you to kind of elaborate and so it's
kind of a it feels like a fun stage
again where we're still we're kind of
relearning or learning new things to be
able to make this stuff actually
work yeah I think I mean everything's
moving so fast and the in like in ways
that really change what you can what you
can and need to build on a product side
because there's a lot of competition
people will immediately clipse you if
you don't actually pick up the the
latest tech yeah that's awesome okay so
back to the AI SDK can you go a little
bit deeper on um what what it is and I
know it also had a recent I think 4.0 um
release as you're kind of constantly
shipping as per usual yeah yeah it like
the asdk basically I would say there's
two things high level um one is like
really just an abstraction layer for the
various model apis out there with a
focus on kind of get getting the
streaming code that nobody runs to write
themselves to be just kind of done um
and I mean there like we've been
iterating and it has lots of like it's
it has lots of like Json forcing related
features lots of uh tool calling related
features and it and lots of kind of
harmonization between models
because as for example model X would
maybe sh native support for something
model B doesn't have it but if use the I
a k you can still switch between them
because the API is exposed through the
SDK is the same for both even if the
underlying implementation is quite
different so that's the one thing which
is basically kind of just utilities for
for connecting to llms and basic and
abstracting that just a little bit
really just a little bit like jdbc in
the in the 90s for databases
um it's not an omm right at this layer
it's like really just saying there's a
way to talk to the database it doesn't
matter way you talk to anthropic open AI
both are exactly the same um and that's
so that's that's that thing the other
side that that we are heavily investing
in is this notion
of connecting UI and
Ai and maybe sometimes confusing we call
it generative UI and maybe if you think
about V zer that's like very
specifically generative UI that's not
what we talking about here like the the
the example app for example that we that
we um use is one where you let's say you
ask the um United Airlines AI that you
want to change your seat and then it
responds with a seat map and then you
pick a seat and then the AI knows what
you just did and so this this whole
cycle of having UI State having AI State
having LM that don't really know what
this UI is like that marshalling between
those things is something that we that
we kind of invest in as kind of the
second big layer in the
asdk got it makes sense and so does that
tie into the uh tool you tool use and
function calling side of things to be
able to integrate these things together
yeah exactly so the there are um several
ways of doing it but like one way is
that if you use react where component
are just functions you can literally
return react components from Tool
calls and so let's say you uh I mean the
simplest example is you ask the AI
what's the weather and so the AI will
invoke the get weather function but that
returns a react component to you know
show you the sun shining and and or
clouds or whatever right um so that's
that's that's uh that's one way to do it
um and then for more complex cases once
you make a change that's done being you
write a little function that says okay
if the user selected seat 17
C that is literally you write a function
that translate that into the user
selected seat 17c so that the llm knows
what's going on because obviously
doesn't really understand what you click
on the AI that makes sense um I'm
thinking about the
jdpc uh metaphor or comparison that you
talking about earlier and that makes a
ton of sense now with respect to uh you
know if you swap out the gdbc driver but
you're using
tsql right you so you can't just kind of
point it to any old database and have it
work and the same thing if you swap out
the model between an open AI model and
an anthropic one that doesn't
necessarily mean you're going to get you
know the same capabilities necessarily
also just like different results uh how
do you see people kind of playing around
with different models
uh with the SDK yeah so I think I think
our learnings are actually somewhat Sur
like they're surprising to me in know
way the gdbc analogies is perfect
because it's really like that we like
the SQL is almost the same right it's
not it's not the same but like you can
get to you can get very far um right if
you don't go into like the darkest
corners of the of the SQL language and
and it's it's I mean I don't I don't
want to over stretch this but basically
what we found is you can switch the
models like because that that doesn't
necessarily need to be true right it
could be that you you're you know I mean
and I'm talking about real applications
but people have spent like months in
like fine tuning the
prompt you know to do something specific
to like you know to handle all kinds of
Ed Edge cases and our experience is that
basically I'm not saying it's like
trivial to change the model but it is
like easier than I at least I would have
expected like it's you you know that you
can talk about how do ideally do it IDE
you have Evas that tell you how well you
do and then you iterate on it but even
basically if you don't if you're not so
sophisticated uh like we just found that
it's like like it seems daunting and
then kind of like apparently they all
converged like enough that it seems to
be an option that's really interesting
because yeah I think I would have maybe
because like if you spent so much time
prompt engineering the hell out of
something and you feel like you've got
something that's working really well you
feel like oh man if I switch from you
know open AI over to anthropic all of
that work could be you know you know
wasted right but if you're saying that
that's not what you're seeing in
practice that's actually kind of awesome
because it means I can like if I'm using
Sonet 35 and I prefer The Vibes in
general I'm I can make that switch
earlier
um and maybe not you know feel much of
the pain it also obviously ties into the
the kind of eval side that you're
talking about where you know we learned
or relearned the power of building
automated tests um in the pre-m world uh
and I know you've You Know spoken and
and posted about kind of the llm world
version of this which is you know eval
driven development can you talk about
what that looks like and how to actually
building feedback loops and like into
building real AI
applications yeah it's like the the the
kind of interesting background is
because I used to work on search we
would have evals like that's literally
how Google works and they would be human
based and this is kind of one of the the
interesting takes is if you look at
Google's upex people obviously know
about the the data centers although
that's mostly capex right um You have to
pay for the power
basically and but it's you know at least
when I was there like a very very very
like incredibly large amount of money
was being spent on humans who would look
at search results and rate them um by
the hundreds and thousands of
queres um and and that you know so it
was straight side by side rate one which
one's better um maybe add why right and
then do it over and over again and and
and so that that method like more or
less translates um right to llms what
what is I think the big difference is
that now you can use llms to do the
rating and they are really good at it
because I mean everyone knows this that
you can you have the situation where the
LM does something and then you ask it
and oh my God yeah now you mention it
right um like it's it's it's just
possible to write like to to have good
like if you know the answer and then you
it's a it's really easy to get an LM to
grade how how how well um the other llm
did right and so you can kind of
automate this but so it's not it's it's
basically like like unit tests but
obviously because LMS are involved it's
kind of slow so like you do have to take
take a bit of a step back um I feel that
always happens when like something truly
new uh is going on I mean don't talk too
much about Google but like for the
longest time there was just no automated
testing for any of the Android apps that
the company was making and these are
like villion user products
right and so like we're kind of in the
same stage where that's just I forgot
about it um but no actually I think
we're doing better right like everyone
understands that that that eils are
needed but they are more difficult to
implement than than than unitest for
Android apps yeah so so like it's a uh
it's definely it's definitely a
challenge it's not it's not fast and I
I'm I you know we use Brain Trust um
we're happy customer but also it is you
know similar to the aisk being Ultra
opinionated Brain Trust is not Ultra
opinionated by this it's not like a you
know like a fully flashed out SAS
Product Where where they like put you
through the onboarding wizard and then
then that's it right that's that's not
yet how it works you do have to like
kind of stick in there and then figure
things out kind makes sense so so uh if
developers think about like what life is
going to be like as a you know AI native
DAV as as we like to talk about it you
know we often talk about the notion in
general in the industry of being a
t-shaped developer right like where are
you Broad and where can you go deep and
uh and I think I saw you mentioning kind
of a little bit about how it can uh you
know you've used you know llms to kind
of you know you have a lot of deep
expertise in areas but it's kind of giv
you conf idence into even areas that you
haven't gone as deep as uh into and kind
of rounding yourself as a developer like
what do you think life's going to be
like in in the future as a as a
developer as all of these you know tools
and everything else get gets better for
us yeah so I think one thing that's
definitely going to happen is that this
like notion of full stack developer is
going to become more true because you if
you know in and that's I mean it's very
similar to the T shaped notion right
because you can you probably deep on
something and then the AI can help you
like go and figure things out in in in
various different areas I think vzer is
actually a really really good example
there and and literally for me because I
am like I like honestly I I don't have
the skill myself to take a figma file
and make a web
page I I don't know how to do that like
I I I can tune CSS but I I cannot go
from scratch like this is not a skill I
have and I've done this for 30 years
so so and V zero can and then it gives
me the thing and I you know it's might
not be perfect but I I do have enough
skills to to to tune it um and I think
so I think this is like just super
powerful for for everyone to kind of go
into domains that they they they they
don't currently feel comfortable
with and and you know I think that's
that's that's almost like unequivocally
a good good thing yeah I was it's been
kind of shocking sometimes to talk to
some Developers just like this is just
like this is just like a junior
developer and it's like okay let's say
it is only a junior developer but it's a
junior developer on everything right
like and it's not actually that Junior
um yeah that's perfect
recall um like I think one one thing
that isn't a thing today but I I Can See
For example incident
analysis uh being a perfect use case
where you where you just answer the
question like okay I understand what's
broken why could it be broken and almost
certainly like some problem like this
has happened in the past but humans
aren't aren't as good at at pattern
matching versus this thing which yeah I
mean absolutely has amazing recall yeah
uh another thing that sometimes comes up
is um you know some fear that developers
may have around just like how are we
going to compete with the you know fan
companies people spending billions of
dollars on Foundation models that have
all of this AI
expertise um you know am I just going to
be had to do some Thin wrapper app and
and that that's kind of it uh what are
your thoughts on uh on you know how AI
is gonna help the the little guy so to
speak I'm I'm actually I'm super
bullish and I'm I'm I will and and my
bull case has like two angles um
the I I because I mean if we don't look
into the future right now um the models
are all
commoditized like Google anthropic
openi and Facebook they all have
essentially equally good
models um and and so they're going to
kind of get this themselves down to the
to the bottom making the product as
cheap as possible
and and and so forth um by the way my
phone started talking to me because
Google
oh hasn't been getting better in though
LMS were invented very very much a
tragedy so so like that so they have
that backdrop of of commoditized models
they're going to get cheaper to invoke
um
and in order to make products good on
them they actually need access to more
data and my impression is that people
underestimate how much proprietary data
they have access
to like one example I've been giving is
let's I mean you can be like very boring
situations but like say I mean not
boring but like like deep but maybe not
like you know I know let's say you make
forklifts no actually better example HV
systems and because that's a bit more
mainstream so everyone needs one
and uh it has documentation and right
now you only give that to like the
certified installers because it's pretty
difficult to consume um I think you
could build like just you know you don't
even have innovate on ux you build an AI
chatbot that does Eli five answers based
on the same documentation that you've
already written and that you've never
published and so so jbt has not not
consumed this um and so you can build
this a relatively differentiated product
I'm not I'm not saying you're to compete
with open the eye with this but but you
get like you can actually add value on
top of something that basically like
that a generic chat B could never uh
kind of achieve without going into like
a very
broad platform strategy which me I'm not
saying they're not trying but they
certainly haven't like been very
successful on on that angle yeah makes
sense okay well I know we're coming up
on time but I have to ask since we both
spent so much of our lives on the on the
open web how do you think AI is going to
help or or harm the web for uh in
general or and for web developers
specifically so one thing that I thought
was very very interesting and is
that when the AI kind of startup boom
happened in San
Francisco
um has it
been a year and a half ago let say and
and since then um there was so such rush
and such exciting excitement and just a
like attitude of getting things out
there that just no one had time to build
native apps like this entire notion that
you would like make three versions of
the thing that you don't know is good
yet and that you're G to throw away in
two weeks because new models coming out
that just not like um like no one was
even considering that like and I think
now it's kind of starting that people
say okay yeah I have my successful
product as a consumer angle let's go
make a native app um like that's coming
but it was such a powerful demonstration
of of how good the web is as a medium to
just like iterate get things out there
that I think that really kind of changed
a lot of people's mind about what the
real priorities are and because I'm not
an anti-native guy but it's certainly
the third thing I'm I'm doing after I
have product Market fit and after things
have settled down a little
bit so I mean and you can talk about
many other things but I think that's
that's a good signal that um there's
just so much value in having a ephemeral
zero friction platform that allows
everyone to get in front of everyone
else yeah awesome molter thank you so
much for taking the time to chat today I
could talk to you for hours about this
stuff uh really excited about what
you're doing at vesel and all of the
tools that you're building to to help us
do all of these great things and uh yeah
look forward to meeting up soon awesome
yeah it was great to see you again and
thanks for having me this super fun
thank you yeah sounds good cheers cheers
bye bye